Finding Aid for the Cornelius Vanderbilt IV Papers
Special Collections and University Archives
- Series II—Writings (Box 4)
  - Writings—Articles (Box 4)
    - Jafsie Condon (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Coolidge (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Luigi Cuiscugi (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Cyrus Curtis (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - D’Anunzio (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Lou Daro (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Robert Dollar (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Dunsany (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Edison (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Edward VIII (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Doug Fairbanks (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Henry Ford (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Elbert H. Gary (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Lloyd George (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Samuel Gompers (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Daniel Guggenheim (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Haig (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Ole Hansen (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Harding (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Hearst (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Hindenberg (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Dean Inge (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Peggy Joyce (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Otto H. Kahn (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - The Kaiser (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Viscount Takakira Kato (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Lindy (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Ben Lindsey (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Ludendorf (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Ramsey Macdonald (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Benarr McFadden (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Mary McElroy (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - O.O. McIntyre (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Marconi (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Bradford Merrill (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Those Mizner Brothers (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Alexander Moore (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Anne Nichols (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Northcliffe (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - John F. O’Ryan (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - John Barton Payne (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Pershing (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Pilsudski (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Tex Rickard (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - John D. [Rockefeller] (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Will Rogers (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Ted R\Roosevelt, Jr. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Rothstein (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Ortis Rubio (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - David Sarnoff (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Charles Schwab (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Major Seagrove (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sharkey (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Admiral Sims (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Stefanson (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Max D. Steuer (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sun, Yat Sen (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Taft (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Bill Tilden (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Three Kings (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Charles Hanson Towne (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Dr. Townsend (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Trotsky (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Gene Tunney (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Alice Tze (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Jimmy Walker (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - H.G. Wells (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Governor White (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - David Wilentz (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Woodrow Wilson (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Walter Winchell (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - De Valera (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - King Zog (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Today or Tomorrow in Your Own Great State—California" (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Today or Tomorrow in Your Own Great State—California (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - B (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Uniform Laws for Foreigners (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - The United States Line (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Vanderbilt Calls New Kyne Novel 'Event of National Importance' (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Vanderbilt's First Interview with Stalin" (2 copies) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - A Victim of Artificiality (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - [Voting Patterns, 1937] Untitled (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Lillian Wald, the Angel of Henry Street (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Washington—Where Our Great Northwest Began (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - What Has Become of the Four Hundred (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Watch Bob Hannegan (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Watch Out Japan" (2 copies) (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - What I Saw in Europe's Last Hour of Peace" (2 copies) (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - What the Japanese Fishermen Really Know" (2 copies) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - What Was Accomplished by the First Cross Section of American Opinion" (2 copies) (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - What Young Mussolini Learned in Hollywood (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - When the Author 'Beat' the Continent (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - When the Windsors come to Hollywood (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Who's Who in Hollywood and Why (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Why Maeterlinck Did Not Impress America (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Why Seattle's Municipally Owned Street Railway Is the Greatest Scandal of, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Wife Made Him Prime Minister, Baldwin Hopes She's Satisfied (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - The Wonderful Future for Industrial British Columbia (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - 'Yacht Trade' White Slave Trade Opens (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - 'Yacht Trade' White Slave Trade Opens (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Writings—Scrapbook (Box 15)
    - “Clippings by a Cub Reporter, 1919–1920” (Box 15)
  - WRITINGS—SCRAPBOOK (Box 16)
    - “Newspapers Columns, 1920–1922 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt,”, 1945–1947 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Writings—Newspaper Columns and Lectures (Box 17)
    - Newspaper Columns, 1921 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Columns, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Columns, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Columns, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Columns, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Columns, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Lecture: “From Roosevelt to Roosevelt,”, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Lecture: Untitled, 1943–1935 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lecture: Northwestern Lecture, n.d. (2 copies) (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Lecture: Untitled, n.d. (2 copies); also lecture draft (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Lecture: Reports about Lectures, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Writings—Lecture Notes and Radio Scripts (Box 18)
    - Publicity Materials for Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s Lectures (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Untitled Lectures, 1930s (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Excerpts from a Vanderbilt Talk, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Graduation Address—Steed Air Force Base Helicopter School, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - “Hotels and Restaurants the World Over, 1940” (2 copies) (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Special Quotes from Vanderbilt’s Latin America Talk, n.d. (2 copies) (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Five Untitled Lectures, 1934–1939 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Radio Script!–“The Die Hards,”, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - First Broadcast for Steven’s Candy, 1930s (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Second Broadcast for Steven’s Candy, 1930s (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Radio News Service, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Script, January 19, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Script, January 26, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Script, February 2, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Script, February 9, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Script, February 16, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Script, February 23, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Script, March 1, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Script, March 8, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Script, March 15, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Script, March 22, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Script, March 29, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Script, April 5, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Scripts, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - “The Cornelius Vanderbilt Show,”, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV Audition, December 7, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Radio Interview—Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Bob Trout, January 15, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Radio Interview with Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Lowell Thomas, 1930s (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Radio Interviews with Cornelius Vanderbilt IV (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV School Papers, Written for School Assignments (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Writings—Notes for Books and Book Manuscripts (Box 19)
    - Notes for The Trailer Book, unpublished (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Notes for Ranches and Ranch Life in America, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Notes for Queen of the Golden Age, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Rough Drafts for Queen of the Golden Age, Part I (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Rough Drafts for Queen of the Golden Age, Part II (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Rough Drafts for Queen of the Golden Age, Part III (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Rough Drafts for Queen of the Golden Age, Part IV (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Rough Drafts for Queen of the Golden Age, Part V (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Rough Draft for The Greatest Frontier, 1920—unpublished—also known as Go West, Young Man, Go West (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Book Manuscript—Personal Experiences of a Cub Reporter, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Book Manuscript—Reno (Swing Your Partners), 1929 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Writings—Book Manuscripts (Box 20)
    - Publisher’s Dummy—Farewell to Fifth Avenue, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Book Manuscript—A Woman of Washington, 1937 (Pp. 1–70) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Book Manuscript—A Woman of Washington, 1937 (Pp. 71–116) (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Book Manuscript—Queen of the Golden Age, 1956 (Part I–Chapters 1–3) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Book Manuscript—Queen of the Golden Age, 1956 (Part II, Chapters 4–6) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Book Manuscript—Queen of the Golden Age, 1956 (Part III, Chapters 7–9) (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Book Manuscript—Queen of the Golden Age, 1956 (Part IV, Chapters 10–11 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Book Manuscript—Queen of the Golden Age, 1956 (Part V–Chapters 12–14) (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Queen of the Golden Age was also published in England in 1957 under the title,The Vanderbilt Feud (Box 20)
- Additional Writings Are Contained in Scrapbooks at the End of the Collection–Boxes 36–45
  - Series III—Business Papers and Personal Papers (Box 21)
    - Receipts, Cancelled Checks, etc. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Trust Information (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Vanderbilt’s Illustrated Daily News Legal Documents (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Contracts (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Court Transcripts (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Memoranda Concerning the Styles–O’Connor Case (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Patents, 1916, 1921 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Copy of Cornelius Vanderbilt III’s Will (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s Marriage License, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s Will (1967) and Life Insurance Form (1968) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Business Proposals (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Directory for the First Session, Council of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Ebenezer Johnston Family Genealogy (Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s Mother’s Family) (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Information about Jacobus Baltius, son of Bartolemeus van der Bilt (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Information about Richard T. Wilson (Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s Maternal Grandfather) (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Mementoes of Grace Vanderbilt (Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s Mother) (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - “The Ghosts of My Friends,” Boyhood Memento (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Adolescent Notes, 1914 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Information about the Vanderbilt House at 640 Fifth Avenue, New York City (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - New York Yacht Cruise, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Membership Application, National Union for Social Justice (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Greeting Cards (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Christmas Card List (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - The London Times, Air Edition, May 25, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Vanderbilt University Centennial Celebration, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Publicity (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - 1949 Summer Schedule (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Commendation from the FBI, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - U.S. Army Active Duty Orders, March 13, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Wedding Publicity, 1948 (Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Patricia Wallace) (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Inventory (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Partial Inventory of Memorabilia (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Obituary and Condolence Notes (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - “A Memory of Cornelius Vanderbilt,” Bernice Sharlach, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Personal Papers (Box 22)
    - "Girls Whom I Know," Notebook, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Series IV—Photographs (Box 23)
    - Late 19th and early 20th Century Studio Portraits (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - School Days and Boating, Early 20th Century (Box 23)
    - France, World War I (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Cornelius and Feliza Pablos Vanderbilt, 1946–1947 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Cornelius and Patricia Wallace Vanderbilt, 1948–1953 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Arizona, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - California, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Nevada, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Rouen, Le Havre, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Denmark, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Photographic negatives, Mexico, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Photographic Negatives, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous People and Places, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Postcards and Photographs, 1920s and 1930s (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Friends, 1950s–1960s (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Friends, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Friends, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Friends, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Cornelius Vanderbilt IV and Friends, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Photographs (Box 24)
    - Norway, n.d. (Roll 2–67) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Norway, n.d. (Roll 2–68) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Norway, n.d. (Roll 2–69) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Aboard the "Venus," Norway to England, n.d. (Roll 2–70) (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Aboard the "Venus," n.d. (Roll 2–71) (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Denmark, n.d. ((Roll 2–72) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll 2–73) (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll 2–74) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 12) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 13) (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 14) (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 15) (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 16) (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 17) (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Europe, n,d, (Roll # 18) (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 19) (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 20) (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll # 21) (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Europe, n.d. (Roll 24) (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Series V—Reviews (Box 24)
    - Reviews of Palm Beach, 1931 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Reviews of Farewell to Fifth Avenue, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Reviews of Man of the World: My Life on five Continents, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Reviews of Reno, a film adapted from the novel, Reno, by Cornelius Vanderbilt IV (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Reviews of the Film, Reno (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Reviews of the Film, Reno (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Series VI—Clippings (Box 25)
    - Clippings, 1897–1901 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1902 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1904 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1905 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 1906 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1907 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1908 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1909 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1910 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1912 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1917 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1919 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1919 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Clippings, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Clippings, 1921 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Clippings, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Clippings, 1922; (Visit to Vanderbilt University for Opening of Vanderbilt's Stadium) (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1922; (Visit to Vanderbilt University for Opening of Vanderbilt's Stadium) (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1923 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1924 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1924 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1929 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1931 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1933–1934 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, 19337–1939 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1940s (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1950s (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Clippings, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, 1960s (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Envelopes Which Contained the Clipping Collection (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Series VII—Writings by Others (Box 27)
    - "A Norite of the Sudbury Type in Manitoba," R.J. Colony, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 1–4, George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 5–7, George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 9–12 (Chapter 8 missing), George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 13–16, George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 17–20, George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 21–24, George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - The Vanderbilt Tabloids, Chapters 25–26, George Duraind, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - "Japan, Philippines," (incomplete), Edmund L. Filmer (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Greenwich Time, December 23, 1937—"The Future of America," Col. Edward M. House (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Greenwich Time, December 30, 1937—"I Am Plain Scared," Hendrik Willem van Loon (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Greenwich Time, February 17, 1938—"Brass Tacks or Foreign Policy," Lothrop Stoddard (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Greenwich Time, February 24, 1938—"A Challenge to Leadership," Frank Altschal (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Greenwich Time, March 10, 1938—"The Land of Blah," Samuel G. Blythe (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - "Dr. Karl's Notes on Current Reading," Karl Menniger, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - "The Motion Picture and the World Today," Louis B. Mayer, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - "As I Saw It," Elliott Roosevelt, 1947 (This file is just an announcement of Elliott Roosevelt's speaking about his book, As I Saw It to the Overseas Presss Club's luncheon, March 26, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - "The World and You," Wendell Wilkie, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - "Challenge to America," W W. Waymack, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Series VIII—Research Notes—Research Notes are on 4 x 6 note cards, arranged alphabetically or by date (Box 28)
    - Research Notes and Articles for Script Magazine, A–Z, 1930s (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Partial Index of Cornelius Vanderbilt IV's Articles for Script Magazine, 1940–1947 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Research Notes and Articles for Script Magazine, A–B, 1940s (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes and Articles for Script Magazine, C–N, 1940s (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes and Articles for Script Magazine, P–Z, 1940s (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Trips and Cruises, 1936–1940: Spanish Trip (Around the World) (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Stardust II—America, 1938 (Box 31)
    - Stardust II—America and Canada, 1938 (Box 31)
    - Royal Visit—America and Canada, Summer, 1939 (Box 31)
    - Balkan Trip—, 1939 (Box 31)
    - Stardust III—Re Neutrality Bill, 1939 (Lecture Tour) Caribbean Cruise, 1940 (Box 31)
    - Research and Reference Notes on People, A–B (Box 31)
    - Research and Reference Notes on People, C–H (Box 32)
    - esearch and Reference Notes on People, I–P (Box 33)
    - Research and Reference Notes on People, Q–Z (Box 34)
    - Lecture Notes and Radio Scripts, 1930s–1950s—No order, either by topic or date (Box 34)
    - Lecture Notes and Radio Scripts, 1930s–1950s—No order, either by topic or date (Box 35)
  - Series II—Writings—Scrapbooks (Box 36)
    - Clippings by a Cub Reporter, 1919–1920 (Box 36)
    - The Far West, 1920 (Box 36)
    - Personal Syndicate and Editorial Comments, 1921 (Box 37)
    - Political Columns, 1922–1923 (Box 37)
    - The Western Series, 1923 (Box 38)
    - "The Illustrated Daily News,", 1923 (Box 39)
    - The Illustrated Daily News, Volume I, 1923–1924 (Box 40)
    - The Illustrated Daily News, Volume II, 1924 (Box 41)
    - The Illustrated Daily News, Volume IV, 1924 (Box 42)
    - "Reno" (the movie), 1930 (Box 43)
    - Lectures and articles, 1939 (Box 43)
    - "Vagabonding with Vanderbilt," February 26, 1946–December 3, 1946 (Binder missing– First two pages contain signatures and good wishes for his marriage to Maria Feliza Pablos (Box 44)
    - Publicity about Lecture Tours, 1950s (Box 45)